<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<suppressions xmlns="https://jeremylong.github.io/DependencyCheck/dependency-suppression.1.3.xsd">

    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
        False positive: spring-boot-netty is Spring Boot's own integration module, versioned
        to match Spring Boot's own release (4.1.0) - it is not the Netty library itself. The
        real Netty here is 4.2.15.Final (see the io.netty:netty-* artifacts in the dependency
        tree). The CPE matcher collides on the coincidental version-number match with the
        real, old netty:netty:4.1.0 release from ~2016.
        ]]></notes>
        <filePath regex="true">.*spring-boot-netty-.*\.jar$</filePath>
        <cpe>cpe:/a:netty:netty</cpe>
    </suppress>

    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
        False positive: spring-kafka's own version number (4.1.0) coincidentally matches the
        CPE for the real, old Spring Framework 4.1.0 (2014). The actual Spring Framework in
        this project is spring-core 7.0.8, unaffected by CVE-2016-5007.
        ]]></notes>
        <filePath regex="true">.*spring-kafka-.*\.jar$</filePath>
        <cpe>cpe:/a:pivotal_software:spring_framework</cpe>
    </suppress>

    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
        False positive: CVE-2018-1258 was fixed in Spring Security 4.2.4 / 5.0.3 (2018). All
        Spring Security modules here (spring-security-core, spring-security-web, ...) share
        the same 7.1.0 version, far newer than the vulnerable range - the NVD CPE match for
        this old CVE does not correctly bound the affected version range against modern Spring
        Security releases. No filePath restriction on purpose - applies to any module in this
        family, same reasoning as the Kotlin suppression below.
        ]]></notes>
        <cve>CVE-2018-1258</cve>
    </suppress>

    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
        Out of scope: CVE-2026-53914 is unsafe deserialization in the Kotlin compiler's build
        cache metadata (CWE-502) - a build-time risk for projects that invoke the Kotlin
        compiler/Gradle build cache. This project is pure Java/Maven and never runs the Kotlin
        compiler or its build cache; every org.jetbrains.kotlin artifact here (kotlin-stdlib*,
        kotlin-reflect, kotlin-stdlib-common, ...) is only a transitive runtime jar pulled in
        via okhttp -> okio (used by the Anthropic Java SDK) or similar. No filePath restriction
        here on purpose - this CVE doesn't apply to any runtime Kotlin jar regardless of which
        one it gets matched against. (Also: 2.4.20 is not yet published as a stable Maven
        Central release, only a beta, so pinning to it isn't currently possible either.)
        ]]></notes>
        <cve>CVE-2026-53914</cve>
    </suppress>

</suppressions>
